你看这几
Lookl
是不是风景极佳
lsn't it spectacular herey?
再来看看这边
Take a |ook over here.
这房子采光特别好
The sun comes in everywhere.
假如你喜欢的话 不用太操心租金 全部我来承担
You dont need to worry about the rent. 川 take care of 革.
我刚有了一份很不销的新工作
They just offered me a good job.
可以解决我们的经济问题
上tl solve our financial problems.
你打算什么时候告诉我 我殴打算在这儿告诉你
When were you going to tell me? 1 wanted to tell you here.
你到磺喜不喜欢
Do you like it or not?
我党得非常完美
| 人 its perfectl
你今天特么了
Whats with you today?
明天我想见见埃利奥诺拉
| want to See Eleonora tomorrow.
为什么 我要和她谈谈
Why? 1 need to talk to her.
我想知道她对于我们的事了解多少
| want to know what she knows about us，
你是什么时候离开家的 你们有多久没睡在一起了
when you left home, how long it's been since youve slept together.
我想类站她父母亲 知不知道你们的婚姻已经结束了
Do her father and mother know your marriage is over?
你可以问我 假如有什么事情不清茎 我可以给你解释
Ask me, isome thing's not clear 1 explain it to you.
不 我只相信她说的
No, | only trust her.
你一直都在说诉
You're a liar.
你怎么突然这么大脾气
What's all this fuss?
别碰我 你这比狗屎
Stop it you piece of shitl
你以为你糊弄的是谁
Who do you think you're dealing with?
我不会再让你这样及脏的男人其驻
Im not letting an asshole like you fuck with mel
你在做什么
What are you doing?
YA人二
/一日
Calm downl
冷静下来 拜托
Calm downm, please.
我们坐下来冷静一
Let's sit down .
冷静一下吧
Let's calm down.
我们坐下谈 可以吗
Let's sit down .
坐下吧 我会和你解释
咱 explain everything. Let's sit down.
拜托
Please.
你很清栖在去法国之前
Before leaving for France.
我把一切都告诉埃利奥诺拉了
1told Eleonora everything，
但回来之后 事情变得很复杂
but when | returned things got complicated.
她开始及病了 开始做一些事情
She began to act crazy to do things.
有一次她拿了一把刀 想捅到目己的肚子里
Once she went to stab herself in the stomach，
有一次她站在阳台上想要跳下去 我吓得要和死
then she wanted to jump off the balcony, 1 got scared.
最后 没错 我就告诉她 我和你结束了
And in the end, yes, |told her you and | were over.
但是她意识到
But she feed
我所有的缺席 借口 都是为了来见你
all my absences, my exCuses, Were to See you.
你知道她怎么做吗 她假疼什么事儿也没有
So she began to pretend nothing was happening，
她假委相信我是真的要去开会
that | really go to conferences,
假委相信我和你真的结束了
and that | dont see you anymore.
现在我和她惑是活在这样一种假妆里 你惟吗
Now we live jin this Sort of fiction
一切都无比顺利 甚至顺利到我可以和你住在这里
Things are going well, so much so that 1m here.
我可以和你在一起 和你睡觉 随心所欲地和你离开
| can be with you, sleep with youw go away with you.
她心知肚明
9he knows perfectly well，
但是她假半目己什么都不台道
but she acts as if she doeSsn't.
埃茉娜
Elena_.
我不期星你原谅我 我只希望你理解我
1dont want you to excuse me.1only want you to understand me.
你对我讽了六 你对她也说了放
You lied to me, to her.
你这么做 并不是出于对我们中任何一个人的爱
You didn't do it forthe love of either of US.
不 不是真的
No, that's not true.
残是真的 你只是为了你目己
Yes, itis. You only did it for yourself.
因为你是一个儒夫 你没有勇气做出选择
You're a coward without the courage of your convictions.
埃茉娜 也许我销了 我请求你的原琢
Elena, may be | was wrong, but 1 apologize.
我这样做 只是为了避免碍剧
1 did { to avoid a tragedy.
我回你保证 我们可以昌无障碍地在一起
| can do whatever | want
你看 我们甚至可以共同拥有一个公寓
We can even get an apartment together.
我们之间已经结束了
It's over between US.
第26章 离散
你为什么要这样 你不可以再打到这里来了 你懂吗
Why are you being like this? Never call me again, understood?
我介了 你让我冷静一下吧
Understood You need to leave me alone.
我做不到啊 尼话 你他妈的 够了
How can 1l? Nino, for fuck's sake, stop it!
够了 不那你融得告诉我 我要怎么做才行
Stop it Tell me what 1 can do.
你他妈的根本没仅 我让你滩开
You dont understand shit now fuck of
我来接
| get it.
Hello?
我是玫拉 我找埃莱娜
Its Lila. lm looking for Elena.
好的
我马上去叫她
1 get her right away.
你的朋友在等你接电话
Your friend's on the phone.
Hello?
莱农 一切都好吗
Lenu, how are things?
N
A
不能怎么样呢 莉拉 你一直在都灵吗
How do you think? Are you stillin Turin?
是的 我还能去哪儿呢
Yeah, where else would | be?
你好吗
How are you?
我很好 好极了 你别操心了
Fine, don't sweat 洲.
生么个好法 和我说说
Come on, talk to me.
我很忙 你保重吧
|m busy, take care.
你在做什么
What are you doing?
我在试图阻止你用家乡话 说出更多粗鲁的话
Trying to prevent you from saying vulgar things in your dialect，
不是什么光彩的场面
its not a pretty ft
你别管我 管好你目己
Look who's talking.
什么章思 你目己心里清楚
What does that mean? You know.
我一点儿也不清和芭
| don't know at al|.
役得罗跟我说 你有过情人
Pietro told me youve had lovers.
我吗 对 融是你
Mey? Yes, yoOu.
不要假闻惊讶了
Dont act so surprised.
我在所有人面前 承担了我的责任
| accepted my responsibilities in front of everyone,
包括售生和艾尔沙 我会付出我该付出的代价
even Dede and Elsa, and 1m suffering the consequences of my actions.
你呢 你半出一副圣洁的样子
But you, you give yourself so many airs,
你是一个虚伪的资产阶级 你把那些脏事隐藏在地毯下面
youre only a little bourgeois /hypocrite who sweeps her dirt under the rug.
你是一个坏女人
You're a bad person.
你根本无法明白真正爱一个人 放弃一个爱的人
You dont know what it means to truly love someone,，
意味着什么
and give them up.
你看上去温顺 客气
You seem docile, shy，
但是你外表下 隐藏着一种非单粗鲁的本性 想所取一切
but you're concealing a craving to "grab everything，
任何东西 包括学习 写书 都没办法训服这种本性
and neither study nor books can change that.
塔尼姬
Tanial
不好意思 女士
Excuse me, ma'am.
我只是感到很遗憾
lm only sorry,
孩子们不能在这里长大
the girls wont grow up here,
她们本可以避免成为你的样子
they might have tried not to be like you.
蜂
塔尼娅 秀驾
Tania, please,
帮埃茉娜打包一下孩子们的行李
help Elena and the girls pack their bags.
我自己来吧
| do it myself.
来目佛罗伦柜的列车即将到达13站人台
The train from Florence is arriving on platform 13.
我们今晚睡哪儿
Where will we sleep tonight?
我们什么时候回爷爷奶奶那里
When are we going back to our grandparents'?
我俄了 我也是 你们安静一操
Im hungry. Calm down.
我们要去那不勒斯 为什么
We're going to Naples. Why?
没有为什么 去尼诡那里吗
Because we are To Nino'S?
开往那不勒斯的列车 即将于6号站人台友车
The train for Naples is leaving from platform 6.
来吧
Come on.
跟上
Hurry up.
我想在没有事和通知的情况下 去尼诺和埃利奥话拉住的地方
|thought of showing up unannounced at Nino and Eleonora's,
告诉他 我和两个女儿的这种处境
所 tell him that 寺 my daughter s and 1 were in this Situation
这也是他造成的 他应该付出代价
让was also his fault and he had to pay.
我想把他也卷入我现在的处境 让他也陷入混乱
| wanted my turmoil to overwhelm him，
残如同我如今的混乱一般
as it was overwhelming me.
开往米三的列车 将于19号站人台友车
The train for Milan is leaving from platform 19.
你们跟上 我们去哪儿
Come. Where are we going?
快一点
Quick.
上和车吧
Get on.
帮有我一下
Help me.
可以帮有我放一下吗 你目己放
Wilyou put mine up? Do it yourself.
我俄了
Im hungry.
一件一件事来
One thing at a time.
你可以给我们奶奶做的三明治吗
Can we have Grandma's sandwiches?
开往米三的列车即将友和车
The train for Milan is departing.
不是旅客请及时下车
Those not traveling are asked to leave.
为什么我们又要去米三了
Why did you decide to go to Milan now?
我想要那个香肠三明治
| want the Salami sandwich .
奶奶是给我做的 不是的
Grandma gave it to me. That's not true.
闭嘴 吃你的吧 我要你的
Shut up and eatl | want yoursl
9Stop it
那是我的
Its minel
我这了 够了
1 Said stop it
只有在列车上 我才意识到目己
Only on the train did | realize the reason,
为什么会忽然改变目的地
forthat abrupt change of plan.
无论如何 我心里的爱在翻江倒海
In spite of everything, love writhed ferociously inside me，
任何伤害尼诺的计划 都让我很厌恶
and the very thought of hurting Nino was repugnant to me.
关于女性的独立 我已经里里外外 写了 思考了很多东西
Even though by the n 1 wrote and thought only about women's autonomy.
但我没办法离开他的身体 声音和办慧
1didnt know how 1d do without his body, his voice, his intelligence.
对我来况 承认这一点非单可介
上was terrible to admit，
但我还是非单渴望他
but | Still wanted him.
我爱他胜过爱我的两个女儿
1loved him more than my own daughters.
我让她们参观一下房子
|上川| Show them the house.
这里呢
And through here.
右边是厨房
The kitchen's on the right.
还有个房间 你们可以在这儿吧饭
There's a room here where you can eat.
这里有我的三个英国朋友
These are three English friends of mine.
她们明天融要离开了
But they're leaving tomorrow.
都是我的朋友
All my frie
那我们的房间呢
And our room?
在那里
In there.
弗三科 在
Francoy? YesS.
看看谁来了
Look who's here.
陛 埃莱娜 路
Hi, Elena.
你好吗 惑那样吧
How are yoOu? 9o0-SO.
妈妈 你过来看
Mamma, come and Seel
-上-二
NA/
/
You're.. ElSsa.
你是 艾尔
你再年长一点 就是售售了
And you, the elder one, are Dede.
降 你可真漂亮 集合
How pretty you arel
我很开心见到你 我也是
lm glad to see you. Me too.
妈妈快来这里 有一把好六的单人椅
a gigantic
我要睡这儿
Im sleeping here.
不 我要睡那儿
No, |m sleeping there,
因为我要睡在妈妈旁边
because 1 want to sleep near Mamma.
去拿行李吧 我们得铺床
Get your luggage. We have to make the bed.
等一下铺
We'l do it later.
你们想在这里待多久都可以 你懂这里的规矩
You can stay as long as you like, you know how things work here.
你也开章我多么爱你
You know how much | love you.
但你不应该那样对我母亲
But you shouldn't have treated my mother that way.
她对我态度很不好 现在是不好
9he behaved very badly. Now.
但之前她帮过你
But in the past she helped you.
她帮有我 只  二 是不     不想让她 LU子丢脸
She only did it so her son wouldn't look bad.
你说这话融不对了 不 我很清切
Youre being unfair. No, 1m being clear.
我也想跟你把话说清楚 我母杀是我母杀
咱 be clear too my mother is my mother,
关于我父杀我哥哥 你想说什么都可以 但你不能说我母亲
Say what you like about my father and my brother but leave her alone.
好了 这里有床单
Here, there are sheets ，
还有毛巾
and towelSs.
如果需要关毯 在这里可以找到
You'll always find blankets in there,
那儿有洽宇
and the bathroom's there.
除此之外 我也不打算把你们当成客人了
And with this, 1m done treating you as a guest.
这个房子属于你们 也属于所有人 你们目便
This house is yours and everyone's, do as you please.
我准备铺床了 你们去洗手吧
Istart putting the sheets on. Wash your hands.
卫生间在那里
The bathroom's there.
Hello?
尼话
Nino.
埃茉娜
Elena_.
你在哪里 在米兰 玛丽娅罗沙这里
Where are you? In Milan, at Mariarosa's.
米兰 你为什么没有来那不勒斯
In Milan? Why didnt you come to Naples?
我来那不勒斯做什么
What for?
你这什么呢 别这样了
Cut iout will you?
没有你 我生么生活
How can | live without you?
我都等你一个月了
lve been waiting for you for a month.
你融像现在这样生活
The way you have so far.
拜托 埃茉娜 不要这样 为什么要这样回答我
Please, stop 让 Why are you talking like this?
事情会慢慢变好的 相信我
Things will sort themselves out.
我早已和航得罗分居了
| stopped sleeping with Pietro.
但你还和埃利奥诺拉睡在一起
But you kept sleeping with Eleonora.
茉农 别再纠结这个了 好吗
Stop fixating on that.
我已经回你解释过了
lve already explained.
如果你不回来 我该怎么办 我受不了了 茉农
fyou dont come back, what will1do? 1 cant go on like this.
你决定好了吗
Have you decided?
决定什么
About what?
决定什么 你还在问我什么
You're asking me about what?
喂 埃莱娜
Hello? Elena.
人允许我解释一下 听我先说完
You gotta let me explain .
妈妈 我吃饱了 不想吧了
| dont want any more.
快吧 别吵
Just eatl
你什么意思 你以为我为什么要租房子
What do you mean, why did I rent it?
回你们房间去 莱农 你听得到吗
Go to your room. Lenu, can you hear me?
咽 我在呢
Yes lm here.
我想你审着孩子们来 住在彼得拉克路
1want you to bring the girls to live in Via Petrarca.
总不           能一直住在那边
用 cant live there forever
还记得那个公寓有多好吗
Remember how nice the apartment is?
我昨天还去了呢 很埋彰
| went back there yesterday, its full of light.
那你呢
What about you?
我来和你们住一起
| come with you.
好 那然后呢
Yeah, and then?
然后什么 埃利奥话拉呢
Then, what? Eleonora?
按我的方式来处理 你听我说 好吗
Lemme do it my way.
我会慢慢安排好一切 我向你保证
| slowly fix everything.
我以我们的爱友壮
| Swear on our |ove.
你明上了吗
You hear me?
明折了吗
我挂了 还有事 再见
1 gotta go, | got things to do.
我要藏在这里
Im hiding here.
别告诉任何人哦
Don't tell anyone.
好 残台在下面吧
Hide, then. Underneath.
这儿没有人 我都听到她进来了
There's no _ one here._But | heard her come in .
你听镑了
You're wrong.
我抓到你了 才没有 你一直输
Im gonna get youl No, you always lose.
不 是我让着你 你每次都大慢了
No, llet you win. You're too slow.
一个女人把目己的身体让渡给了她的孩子
A woman abandons her body to her children,
由他们所吞噬 这惑是我们必须反抗的
she is devoured by them and this is what we must rebel against.
如果无法控制目己身体的话
No woman can define herself as free,，
没有任何一个女人 可以定义自己为自由身
并 she does not have control over her own body.
这是我们必须解决的问题
Thats the issue we must tackle.
我们谈论各种各样的事情
We say this applying it to everything，
但我们从未谈及母性
but we never apply it to motherhood.
而且我非音幸运地 在家邀请到了埃茉娜`格雷科
And since 1am lucky enough to have Elena Greco as my guest.
我希望她对我们襄几名
1d like her to say a few words.
来吧 埃茉娜
Go on, Elena.
(艾尔沙莫三售 意大利音名女作家)
我想从多尔水`莫三售开始讲
| could start with Elsa Morante ，
她说没有人认为  和母邓
who says no one thinks a mother has a woman's body.
对于子女而言 母亲的身体是变化无形的
For sons and daughters mothers have amorphous bodies.
我们也这么认为
Wethought that too,
也许我们会想到我们的母杀
and maybe we still think it about our mothers.
我们应该感到羞愧
We should be ashamed .
我的女儿们也在场 融在这
Then there are my daughters here they are.
可能她们也会这样想
Maybe they also think like that,
会这样看竺我
see me |ike that.
张
得我者 而不是伟大
As old rather than Saintly.
我去开门吗
Shall 1 go?
好的
继续吧
Go on.
和警察来了
Its the police.
晚上好 请问有什么事
Good evening, can | help you?
晚上好 附近居民有上所抱负
A neighbor has complained.
抱怨什么
About what?
说你们这里人很多制造噪音
They say there's people making a racket.
我的一些朋友在这儿 我们在讨论母性
| have Some friends here we're discussing motherhood.
我不知道这能否被定义为太吵
| dondt know ifthat can be defined as a racket.
时间还不晚 你看小朋友都还没睡呢
Its not late seeing as the children are Still up.
不过你们可以进来 不用了 夫人
But ld like you to come in. There's no need, ma'am.
或者应该称呼您为小姐
Or miss.
你们不确定我是订婚 已婚 还是单身 对吗
You cant decide lm engaged, married, or a virgin?
叫我玛丽娅罗范就可以
Mariarosa will do .
进来吧 不用了
Come in. There's no need .
但我想让你们进来 请进
But ld like you to, please, come 月过
这边
This way.
>主
本
Please.
玛丽娅罗水 你是被捕了吗
Mariarosa, have you been arrested?
请便找个位子 随便坐吧
Please, find a seat.
我证明 我姑妈是位教授
1 can guarantee my aunt's a professor.
我辐你们保证 她叫玛丽娅罗沙:艾罗培 教己术史
| assure you her name's Mariarosa Airota,
我们和子女的关系
and she teaches art history.
明上了
| See .
也许我们可以让我们的朋友们
Maybe we could ask our friends to tell us,
况这他们的母亲 说说从小是如何看竺她们的
about their mothers, how they've perceived them since they were little.
抱歉 我们得走了 还有任务
Unfortunately we have to go, we're on duty.
我们已经核实了 已经核实了 是吗
But we've verified _ You've verified?
谢谢你们的配合
Thank you for your kindness.
不客气
You're Welcome.
我们走吧
Let's go.
晚安
Good night.
很好 然后呢
Good So7?
因此 平民的双手
So the common people's arms,
必须用来填满贵族的肚子 否则束会出现膝烦
must work to fi the patricians macl or there's trouble.
但是呢
But?
但是什么
(梅尼乌斯'阿格里由 元言故事人物 证罗马贵族 闭名护教者)
但梅尼乌斯.阿格里由其昭了他们
But Menenius Agrippa tricks them.
稍等 我举个例子
Listen.
艾尔水吧了东西 难道你融不饭了吗 不是的
上fElsa eats, does your hunger go away?
并不会 平民也是如此
No and neither does the common people's,
他们的秀动最后被贵族吞噬了
because their work ends up in the patricians'stomachs.
对不外 我在出版社耽摘了一会儿
Sorry, 1 was held up at the publishers .
玛丽娅罗水呢 她一会儿回来 带着一个惊喜
And Mariarosay? She'l be home later with a surprise.
什么恢喜 是什么 什么尺喜
What surprise? What?
一会儿残知道了
Later.
我票坏了
|'m shattered .
你们在学习吗
Are you studying?
我在复习寓言故事 一篇思权的文章
Im reviewing the "Apologue,"garbage.
为什么这么说 他说的 弗兰科
Why do you say that? He says 比.
妈妈 这文章说我吃东西 但胖的却是你
Its like leat but its you who gets fat.
你说什么 是真的
What? Its true.
我们读完了 对吗
Are we done?
你类道的 那融是读完了 好
Up to you. Yes.
今天真的特别累
Its been an exhausting day.
她们本有可能是我们俩的孩子
They could have been ours.
如果是的话 年龄会大一些
They'd be a bit older now.
姑妇们 你们的苑多来啦
Girls your father's here.
恢喜来了 什么
The surprise has arrived. What?
全外
区区
Papal
你们好呀
Here they arel
让我看看你们
Let me take a look at you.
你们真美 长大了好多啊
Youve grown So muchl
你好 埃莱娜 你好
Hi Elena. Hi.
我们走 你们跟我来 走
Come.
你们在这儿生么样 超级棒
Do you like it here? Heaps.
我们想什么时候睡咒都可以 什么意思
We goto bed when we what. What?
是的 我们每晚都很开心 这里一直都有很多人
We have fun at night. there are always people here.
也不是一直 别太夸张了
Not always, let's not exaggerate.
那你们早上和皇么起得来 我们什么时候起融什么时候学习
How can you get up early? When we get up we Study.
所以 你们真的没去上学吗 她们在这儿学习
So its true you don't go to school. They study here.
有一次警察也来了
Policemen came too.
警察来过这里吗 对 就在这
The police were herey? Yes, right here.
多和莉娅娜生么样
And Doriana?
多夭娅娜
Doriana?
她们在这儿生么学习 我们辅导她们
How do they study here? We help them.
这是暂时的 如果她们留下来 我们可以安排
Its temporary, ifthey stay.…
暂时的
ts temporary.
暂时的标准是什么
And what's the criterion for "temporary"”?
你们融是这样生活的吗
ls this how you and my sister live?
我他妈爱怎么生活都可以
live howthe fuck | want.
至于她们 既没有不开心 也没有变磊
As for them, they seem neither unhappy nor ignorant，
而且我们一直在教她们
and one of us always helps them.
你们俩教吗 在这儿的任何人都可以
One of you? Whoever's here.
任何人
Whoever's here.
你们两个太不负责任了 你意识到了吗
You're Dotps So irresponsible.
你把她们从一个有纪律的家中市走
You took them away from a home where there was discipline,
把她们变成了流溪汉
and turned them into hobosl
你想做什么 你想带走她们吗
Do you want to take them away?
你和多莉娅娜来抚养她们吗 你认为我没有能力吗
You and Dorian a will raise them? You think 1m not capable?
你党得
What do you 号呢
你觉得她们能这样暂时地生活吗
They cant live in a "temporary"situation,
能随便和任何人学习吗 她们可以像其他孩子一样去上学
study with whoever's there not go to school like other kidsl
冷静一下 彼得罗
Calm down.
恕我插嘴 但我也偶尔辅导她们学习
Excuse me for butting in but 1 also help them study.
没错 她们跟来这儿的人学习 我也偶尔参与其中
Sure, they study with whoevers there and when they're lucky it's you.
她们俩很聪明 而且她们在尽可能地学习
The girls are clevenr they study as much as necessary,
她们的理解能力很强
their level of learning is very high.
她们需要规律的生活
They need a regular life.
你的文儿需要什么 不由我来癌
| dont have to tell you what your daughters need.
的确 我来告诉你 告诉你们所有人
In fact, Ttell you. All of you.
她们需要万法 需要标准化
They need method, a criterion.
这个家里有很多人
This house is full of people,
在这儿人们会演奏 讨论
who play music who discuss things.
我认为我也不喜欢 我总是把目己关在房间
1dont like it either hm always shut away in my room.
但这也是一个标准化的事情
But that's also a criterion ，
只不过是暂时的
definitely temporary.
埃莱娜和孩子们都不会符太入
Neither Elena nor the girls will stay here for long.
但是我训实话 等她们长大后
But when they're grown Up，
在这儿的日子 会是她们最美好的回忆之一
among their best memories will be the days spent here,
在玛丽并罗水家的日子
at MariaroSsa'S.
或许的确如此
That's probably right,
我对此并不感到遗憾
and | cant be sorry about 雍
但我们必须拉心目问
but the question we have to ask is,
她们能回归正常的生活吗
willthey be able to go back to a regular life?
如果大人都做不到 何况她们呢
ff adults struggle to do it imagine them.
在你父母那里 她们有一个家
At your parents' they had a family，
但在这里 她们也有
but they have one here too.
并且在这里 她们更快乐
And its more fun for them.
弗三科 你并没有回答我的问题
You didnt answer my question.
她们会被强迫适应 会反击 但最后会届服
They'l be forced, they'fight back but then they'l give in.
我很抱歉
Forgive me.
只是太担心你们 我希邓你们得到世界上最好的
But lm worried about you, 1 only want what's best for you.
你们妈妈和我在这一点上 无疑达成了共识
Your mother and | agree on this.
是的 是这样
YeS, its true.
波得罗是对的
Pietro was right.
对我女儿来说 正确的选择
What was right for my daughters,
并不是我之前说服自己的那样
was not what 1d convinced myself it was.
她们的确应该与别人相处
They needed to be with others,
需要日程安排 家庭作业 还有同伴
to have Schedules homework, classmates.
我可以跟你回家去吗
Can lcome home with you?
别任性
Dont act up.
至少你要陪我进去吧
Wilyou take me inside?
杀爱的 如今已经两个多礼拜了
Its been more than two weeks now，
老师都况你应该更独立一些
the teacher said you need to be more independent.
去吧 我会看着你的
Go, 上川 watch you.
(米兰市政 拉维妮娅-方塔娜小学)
我看着呢 去吧
Im watching, go.
那些白子我都在鄙视目己
| spent those days despising myself.
我无法将尼话从脑海中抹去
| couldn't get Nino out of my head.
我将近三个月没有见他
| hadnt seen him for nearly three months,
我目己也承认 我非常想他
and 1admitted to myself | missed him a lot.
我一直都很想他
|thought of him all the time.
甚至城市的每个街道都让我想象
Even the city streets made me imagine,
我和他一起走在这里 会是什么样子
what ii would be like 1walked them with him，
送完孩子 我们一起回家会是什么样
并we came back from the School together after dropping off the girls.
你怎么在这儿
What are you doing here?
我昨晚从那不勒斯出友的
1left Naples last night.
我们聊会儿吧 我快疯掉了
Lets take a moment |m losing my mind.
如果 离我远点
What 计..? Let go of mel
茉农 我这了 离我远操
1 Said, let go of mel
如果我一走了之 丈间大祸了
上1leave all hell will break looSsel
我知道的
结果会如何呢
And what would the result be?
会永远没法安子地和你生活
That 1 could never live peacefully with you.
尔得听我说 莱农
You have to listen to_ me.
我了解埃利奥诺拉
| know Eleonora.
我了解会有友生什么
| know what could happen.
你到辰在说什么
What are you Saying?
我襄我不能离开挨利奥话拉
| cant leave Eleonora，
但没有你 我根本无法生活
but lcant live without you.
那我的理解没有错
你给我的提议是
you're suggesting as a reasonable solution,，
让我改变情人的身份 做你的第二个妻子
that 1 give up the role of mistress to be a parallel wifel
这个意思 不是这样 明明惑是
1 didn't say thatl Yesl
硕是这样的 不是
ltis like thatl No
AN一
NDS
/
Go awayl
从哪来 回哪去
Go back to where you came froml
我来这儿和你说清芭 我不想让别人来告诉你
1 came to tell you Something, 1 dont want you to hear from others.
说来听听
Let's hear 放.
你想知道我为什么这样做吗
You want to know why | behaved like that?
因为埃利奥诺拉已经怀孕七个月了
Eleonora is seven months pregnant.
所以现在我很难离开她
That's why it's so hard to leave her now.
把他赶出去
Throw him out
拜托 把他赶走
Please, throw him out.
你在那等一下
Wait in there.
把他赶走
Throw him outl
Here.
埃茉娜
Elena_.
Sit down .
Come on. Sit down.
求你了 把他赶走
Please, throw him out.
弗明科 把他赶走
Franco, throw him out.
他的妻子已经怀孕七个月了 他一直在骗我
His wife's seven months pregnant he lied to me the whole time.
好吧
All right.
他没有逃走
He didnt run away，
他到这儿来告诉你
he came all this way to tell you.
他开了一晚上
He traveled all night.
一定是有理由的 这这明他是一个统子
上must mean something. 此means that he's a liar.
一个很轻浮的人 他没办法作出选择
That he's superficial, incapable of choosing.
我知道
| know.
我知道 你是对的
| know, you're right.
如果他只能这样爱你呢
What ifthat's the only way he can love you?
你也滚开
Fuck you, too.
我得习惯没有你的生活
| have to get used to living without you.
现在还很艰难
Right now it's hard.
但我离开你无法生活
But lcant live without you，
你和任何人 任何事都无法分开
from anything or anyone.
不 那不是真的
No, that's not true.
为了得到你 我不得不留下其他的
To keep you gotta hold onto everything.
你走吧
GO away.
你现在打算霸么办
What will you do now?
为什么姑姑不和我们一起吧晚饭
Why didnt Auntie have dinner with us?
玛丽娅罗水在波尔多 几天后回来
Mariarosa's in Bordeaux, she'll be back in a few days.
波尔多在哪
Where's Bordeaux?
法国
In France.
但是弗明科在吗 对 他在
本
但如果他不从房间里出来 融说明他不钱
上ff he doesnt come out of his room, it means he's not hungry.
你们吧完了吗
Are you done?
去换睡衣
Go get into your pajamas.
妈妈 我们已经穿着睡衣了
We're already in our pajamas.
妈妈大体和时
Sily Mamma.
弗衣科是做什么的
What job doe
他写文章 做研究
He writes, he studies.
我们在比萨认识的 在大学里
We met in Pisa, at university.
他教了我很多事情
He taught me a lot of things.
他是我们学院最出名的
He was the most famous one in our faculty.
所有人都跟随他
Everyone followed him.
你们交往过吗
Did you ever date him?
是的
YeS.
坐吧 吧氮东西
Sit down, eat something.
吧吧 对你有好处
Eat, its good for you.
你们现在去那边玩吧
Now go and play in there.
伍么了
Whats wrong?
和出版社的进展皇么样了
How are things with the publisher?
我丛了合同
| signed the contract
但我一个字还没写
but | havent written a word yet.
出版社想尽快出版
The publisher wants to get it out as soon as possible.
我做不到 我的心思在其他地万
But 1 can't do it my head's somewhere else.
我无法集中精力
Im not foc
有时候我在想 为什么要写另一本书
Sometimes 1wonder "Why should 1 write another book?"
这不是目动完成的事 也不是份工作
Its not automatic' its not a job，
感到被迫做这件事 是没有意义的
feeling obligated to do it is pointless.
你的心思在其他地万 在哪 你知道在哪儿
Somewhere else, where? You know.
我的心思在那不勒斯
My head's in Naples.
在尼诺那里
It's where Nino ijS.
我在考虑回到那里去
Im thinking of going back.
假如你爱他超过爱目己
ff you love him more than yourself
接受他现在的样子吧
take him a
有麦子 孩子
With a wife and kids，
还有和其他女人
and this permanent tendency,
上床的爱好
to fuck other women.
还有他擅长做的
And the sordid things,
其他龋齿事
he'l be capable of .
埃茉娜
Elena, Elena.
你无可款何
No two ways about it.
只有当你做回目己
人 love its over only when you can,
并且腥无是惧或厌烦
become yourself again, without fear
爱情才会结
or disgust.
你们干嘛要跑
Why are you running?
我要去尿尿 尿到裤子里吧 傻子
| gotta peel Do itin your pants dummy.
不许说傻子 放开我 还有你 别尿到裤子里
Dont say dummy. And you don't do it in your pants.
放开她
Leave her alone.
能帮有我摆一下果子吗 杀爱的
Wilyou help me set the tabley?
我们可以在那儿吧吗 可以
Can we eat in there? YeS.
妈妈 看
Mamma, look.
妈妈 这个贴在弗朗科的房间外
This was outside Franco's room.
你为什么摘下来了
Why did you take it down?
你们最近老是打扰他吗
Have you bothered him'a lot lately?
妇1 一      点j
No._ Not at 儿
好吧 那让他一个人竺会儿
Let's just leave him alone.
埃莱娜 不要让两个孩子进来
"Elena, dont let the girls in."
就像唱歌一样
The same as the song.
我们必须歌唱
That we have to sing.
圭子破旧不卉
Worn-out shoes.
但我们必须继续前行
And yet we must march on.
玛丽娅罗沙
MariaroSsa_.
西尔维亚
Silvia.
尼诡
Nino?
为什么
Why?
我原本想等一等再离开
1d have preferred to wait before leaving，
留在玛丽娅罗沙身边
stay close to Mariarosal
但她对我不再是那种姐妹的态度
but she no longer treated me in a sisterly manner，
而是越来越序满政意
and she became increasingly hostile.
如果两个孩子在家里玩的时候弄出声吗 她会非营生气
She got angry ifthe girls made noise playing,
如果我贡驾她们 她会更生气
she got even angrier if1scolded them for their noisy games，
所以我收拾了行李 返回那不勒斯
so | packed our bags and went back to Naples.
当我们重新开始相爱的时候 埃莉奥诺拉还怀着身孕
Eleonora was still pregnant when we began to love each other again.
当她生下一个叫莉迪亚的女孩时
And by the time she gave birth to a girl named Lidia.
尼诺和我早已恢复成一对正芝的情人
Nino and | had already returned to being a couple of lovers,
有着我们目己的生活
with our habits，
漂有的房子 两个孩子
a beautiful house, two girls,
还有非单丰富的生活
and a rather jntense |ife.
但是我和我的女儿们 在那不勒斯做什么呢
But what were my daughters and 1 doing in Naples?
我们只是为了让尼诺高兴吗
We were there only to make Nino happy.
我做出一副目由独立的样子 我是在说详吧
| was lying when | acted free and autonomous,
我在欺骗我的听众 尽管我说了那么多
and |was lying to my audience despite all my talk
但我还是让一个男人捏造我 好满足他的需
Since | had let a man control me to the point where his needs,
高于我和两个女儿的需:
prevailed over mine and my daughters'.
从佩特拉卡大街看过去 城区很远 融像一个苑昌的石头堆
From Via Petrarca, the neighborhood was a pale, distant memory.
我可以反复告诉目己 我现在成了另一个人
1 could tell myself 1 was someone else now,
这里和我再也没有任何瓜葛了 但事实并非如此
and | had nothing to do with it anymore, but that wasn't the case.
我还是在不断地出现在这里
| kept showing up to see it.
我知道我已经没有借口逃避了
| knew | was out of excuses，
是时候去直面它了
iLwWastime | dealt with 汪